# Tommy Roberts

#### **Game Designer**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/-tommy-roberts/ tommyrobertsms@gmail.com (224) - 244 - 2609 troberts2.github.io

As a passionate and dedicated game programmer, I am driven by the desire to bring immersive and engaging gaming experiences to life. With a solid foundation in programming languages such as C++, C#, and Python, I have honed my skills through coursework and personal projects, demonstrating my ability to design, implement, and optimize game mechanics and systems. I thrive in collaborative, creative environments and relish the opportunity to work alongside talented designers and artists to transform ideas into interactive realities.

# **Key Skills**

- Game Design: Proficient in designing game mechanics, creating game prototypes, and developing engaging gameplay experiences.
- Game Engines: Familiar with Unity, including level design and scripting.
- Coding: Strong knowledge of programming languages (C#, C++, Java, Python) for game development and object oriented programming.
- User Experience (UX): Understanding of user-centered design principles to enhance player experience.
- Problem Solving: Strong analytical and critical thinking skills to address design challenges.
- Team Collaboration: Effective communication, collaboration, and leadership in multidisciplinary game development teams.
- 2D/3D Art: Basic proficiency in Adobe Creative Suite, Blender.

### **Objective**

Enthusiastic and creative game designer, seeking an internship opportunity to gain handson experience in the game development industry. My fascination with emerging technologies and my commitment to staying up-to-date with industry trends make me eager to contribute to cutting-edge game development projects. Hopeful to contribute my passion for learning more better programming practices, and contributing interesting ideas to a dynamic game design team.

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Science in Game Design; Minor in Computer Science & Information Systems

Bradley University, Peoria, Il | August 2021 - Present

- Game Design Fundamentals
- Game Mechanics and Gameplay
- Object Oriented Programming & Data Structures
- User Experience (UX) Design
- Game Development Tools and Technologies (Mostly experience in Unity)

## **Proficient Software Development Languages**

C#, C++, Java, Python

## **Professional Experience**

#### Pool Manager

Park Ridge Park District | December 2017 - Present

- Trained and supervised a staff of over 150 lifeguards during the summer season.
- Created and maintained an accurate pool schedule.
- Assisted in the development and implementation of pool programming and special events.
- Ensured the smooth and efficient operation of the pool, including maintenance of safety standards, facility cleanliness, and customer service.

#### Front of House Server

Dac's Smokehouse | October 2022 - February 2023

- Provided customers with menus and answered questions about menu items.
- Took orders for food and beverages and delivered orders to guests in a timely manner.
- Processed cash and credit card payments.

#### Package Handler

Fedex | December 2021 - January 2022

Loaded and unloaded packages weighing up to 200lbs with speed and accuracy.